let preguntasActividad = [
    {
        "id": 1,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 1,
        "id_actividad": 1,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "Who told Homer to open the door?",
        "respuesta": "Smithers",
        "opciones": [
            "Smithers",
            "Bart",
            "Marge",
            "Lisa"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/King Size Homer 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 2,
        "id_actividad": 2,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Order the sentence.",
        "respuesta": "This new exercise program is great",
        "opciones": [
            "exercise",
            "program",
            "great",
            "is",
            "This",
            "new"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/King Size Homer 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 3,
        "id_actividad": 3,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Match",
        "pregunta": "Match the sentences with the character who said it",
        "respuesta": "Someone's in here, Homer, This new exercise program is great, Carl, Raise your left hock. Aerate, Mr. Burns",
        "opciones": [
            "Someone's in here",
            "Homer",
            "This new exercise program is great",
            " Carl",
            "Raise your left hock. Aerate",
            "Mr. Burns"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/King Size Homer 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 4,
        "id_actividad": 4,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Complete",
        "pregunta": "Complete the dialogues with the right word.",
        "respuesta": "open, new, hock, each",
        "opciones": [
            "C’mon Simpson. open up. we know you’re in there This new exercise program is great Raise your right hock. Aerate. I want to see more Teddy Roosevelts and less Franklin Roosevelts See. each pushup includes both an up part and a down part"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/King Size Homer 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 5,
        "id_actividad": 5,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "Choose all the characters who participate in this video.",
        "respuesta": "Homer, Smithers, Mr. Burns, Lenny, Carl",
        "opciones": [
            "Homer",
            "Smithers",
            "Marge",
            "Mr. Burns",
            "Lenny",
            "Carl",
            "Bart",
            "Lisa",
            "Maggy"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/King Size Homer 5.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 6,
        "id_actividad": 7,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Number",
        "pregunta": "Number the phrases in the order in which they appeared",
        "respuesta": "This new exercise program is great,2,Someone’s in here,1,It’s like a lottery that rewards stupidity,3",
        "opciones": [
            "This new exercise program is great",
            "Someone’s in here",
            "It’s like a lottery that rewards stupidity"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/King Size Homer 6.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 7,
        "id_actividad": 9,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "Question: Who is talking?",
        "respuesta": "Bart",
        "opciones": [
            "Homer",
            "Lisa",
            "Bart"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 7,
        "id_actividad": 16,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "What hardship did Frank Grimes face during his childhood?",
        "respuesta": "He delivered toys to fortunate children",
        "opciones": [
            "He lost his family in an accident",
            "He delivered toys to fortunate children",
            "He suffered from a disease",
            "He attended an elite school\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 7,
        "id_actividad": 21,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Rearrange the following words to form a coherent sentence:",
        "respuesta": "Frank delivered toys as a delivery boy to more fortunate children",
        "opciones": [
            "Frank",
            "delivered",
            "as",
            "a",
            "boy",
            "toys",
            "delivery",
            "to",
            "children.",
            "fortunate",
            "more\""
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 8,
        "id_actividad": 10,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "What is Homer’s primary motivation to gain weight in the episode \"King-Size Homer\"?",
        "respuesta": "To avoid physical work",
        "opciones": [
            "To improve his health",
            "To avoid physical work",
            "To gain popularity",
            "To set a weight record\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 8,
        "id_actividad": 17,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "How did Frank Grimes gain his education?",
        "respuesta": "Studied science by mail",
        "opciones": [
            "Attended night classes",
            "Studied science in university",
            "Studied science by mail",
            "Learned from his parents\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 9,
        "id_actividad": 11,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "What unusual advice does Dr. Nick give Homer to help him gain weight?",
        "respuesta": "Consume all-fat diet",
        "opciones": [
            "Exercise daily",
            "Avoid junk food",
            "Eat mostly vegetables",
            "Consume all-fat diet\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 9,
        "id_actividad": 18,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "What decision does Mr. Burns make about Frank Grimes?",
        "respuesta": "To make him executive vice president",
        "opciones": [
            "To make him his chauffeur",
            "To make him his assistant",
            "To make him executive vice president",
            "To have him repair a silo\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 9,
        "id_actividad": 22,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "Which of the following describes Frank Grimes's experiences? (Select all that apply):",
        "respuesta": "He was injured in a silo explosion,He gained a nuclear physics diploma\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "He studied science in a conventional school",
            "He was injured in a silo explosion",
            "He gained a nuclear physics diploma",
            "He attended Springfield Elementary\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 10,
        "id_actividad": 12,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "How does Marge react when she finds out about Homer’s weight gain plan?",
        "respuesta": "She’s disappointed",
        "opciones": [
            "She supports it",
            "She joins him",
            "She’s disappointed",
            "She encourages him to lose weight\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 10,
        "id_actividad": 19,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following phrases in the correct order:",
        "respuesta": "Kent’s People. Tonight’s inspiring story is about Frank Grimes… A real scrapper. Bring this Grimes fellow to me.",
        "opciones": [
            "Bring this Grimes fellow to me.",
            "Kent’s People.",
            "A real scrapper.",
            "Tonight’s inspiring story is about Frank Grimes…\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 10,
        "id_actividad": 23,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following sentences in the correct order:",
        "respuesta": "Then. on his eighteenth birthday... he was blown up in a silo explosion. During his long recuperation. he taught himself to hear... Bring this Grimes fellow to me. He pulled a toddler from the path of a speeding car...\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "He pulled a toddler from the path of a speeding car...",
            "During his long recuperation. he taught himself to hear...",
            "Bring this Grimes fellow to me.",
            "Then. on his eighteenth birthday... he was blown up in a silo explosion.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 11,
        "id_actividad": 13,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following phrases in the order they appear in the episode: ",
        "respuesta": "I don’t want to look like a weirdo. You’ll want to take in plenty of empty calories. Ooh. the floor feels really good on my stomach. I wash myself with a rag on a stick.",
        "opciones": [
            "You’ll want to take in plenty of empty calories.",
            "I wash myself with a rag on a stick.",
            "I don’t want to look like a weirdo.",
            "Ooh. the floor feels really good on my stomach.\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 5.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 11,
        "id_actividad": 20,
        "id_unidad": 1,
        "descripcion": "Match",
        "pregunta": "Match each character with their description or action:",
        "respuesta": "Delivered toys to more fortunate children.,Frank Grimes,Assigned to find a heroic dog.,Smithers,Wants to make Frank Grimes his executive vice president.,Mr. Burns,Studied science by mail.,Frank Grimes",
        "opciones": [
            "Delivered toys to more fortunate children.",
            "Frank Grimes",
            "Assigned to find a heroic dog.",
            "Mr. Burns",
            "Wants to make Frank Grimes his executive vice president.",
            "Kent Brockman",
            "Studied science by mail.",
            "Smithers"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Mother Simpson 5.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 33,
        "id_actividad": 51,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "When is National Moon Day celebrated?",
        "respuesta": "July 20th",
        "opciones": [
            "July 4th",
            "July 2th",
            "August 1st\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 33,
        "id_actividad": 59,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Mach",
        "pregunta": "Match each space program milestone with its significance or consequence:",
        "respuesta": "President Kennedy's announcement of NASA's Apollo space program.,Signaled the beginning of efforts to land a man on the moon.,The first televised images of the moon's surface transmitted by NASA's unmanned probe Ranger 7.,Provided unprecedented visual information about the moon's surface.",
        "opciones": [
            "President Kennedy's announcement of NASA's Apollo space program.",
            "Provided unprecedented visual information about the moon's surface.",
            "The first televised images of the moon's surface transmitted by NASA's unmanned probe Ranger 7.",
            "Signaled the beginning of efforts to land a man on the moon."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 33,
        "id_actividad": 67,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "Which astronauts were involved in the Apollo 11 mission?",
        "respuesta": "All of the above",
        "opciones": [
            "Neil Armstrong",
            "Buzz Aldrin",
            "Michael Collins",
            "All of the above\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 33,
        "id_actividad": 76,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "What was President Kennedy's main goal in announcing NASA's Apollo space program?",
        "respuesta": "To commit the nation to landing a man on the moon before the end of the decade.",
        "opciones": [
            "To emphasize the importance of space exploration.",
            "To propose a mission to explore Mars.",
            "To signal the end of the Cold War.",
            "To commit the nation to landing a man on the moon before the end of the decade.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 34,
        "id_actividad": 52,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "Who made the historic speech announcing NASA's Apollo space program?",
        "respuesta": "President John F. Kennedy",
        "opciones": [
            "Buzz Aldrin",
            "Michael Collins",
            "President John F. Kennedy\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 34,
        "id_actividad": 60,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "Which of the following events are associated with National Moon Day? Select all that apply.",
        "respuesta": "The anniversary of the first moon landing.,President Nixon's declaration of a national holiday.",
        "opciones": [
            "The anniversary of the first moon landing.",
            "President Nixon's declaration of a national holiday.",
            "The discovery of water on the Moon.",
            "The date of the Moon's discovery.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 34,
        "id_actividad": 68,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "What significance did President Kennedy's announcement about NASA's Apollo program have?",
        "respuesta": "It marked the beginning of efforts to land a man on the moon.",
        "opciones": [
            "It marked the beginning of efforts to land a man on the moon.",
            "It emphasized the importance of space exploration.",
            "It signaled the end of the Cold War.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 34,
        "id_actividad": 69,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following sentences in the order they appear in the text:",
        "respuesta": "President Nixon declares National Moon Landing Day on July 20th to celebrate the anniversary of man's first moon landing. NASA announced the moon landing as being “the single greatest technological achievement of all time”. Neil Armstrong was the very first person that steps on the moon.",
        "opciones": [
            "NASA announced the moon landing as being “the single greatest technological achievement of all time”.",
            "President Nixon declares National Moon Landing Day on July 20th to celebrate the anniversary of man's first moon landing.",
            "Neil Armstrong was the very first person that steps on the moon.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 34,
        "id_actividad": 77,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "Which of the following are activities suggested for celebrating National Moon Day?",
        "respuesta": "Visiting a local planetarium.,Watching a movie about the moon landing.,Reading a book about space exploration.",
        "opciones": [
            "Visiting a local planetarium.",
            "Watching a movie about the moon landing.",
            "Hosting a barbecue party.",
            "Reading a book about space exploration.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 35,
        "id_actividad": 53,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "What was the name of the first manned flight on NASA's Apollo eight?",
        "respuesta": "Apollo 8",
        "opciones": [
            "Apollo 11",
            "Apollo 13",
            "Apollo 8\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 35,
        "id_actividad": 61,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "Who were the astronauts involved in the Apollo 11 mission? Select all that apply.",
        "respuesta": "Neil Armstrong,Buzz Aldrin,Michael Collins",
        "opciones": [
            "Neil Armstrong",
            "Buzz Aldrin",
            "Michael Collins",
            "John F. Kennedy\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 35,
        "id_actividad": 70,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following sentences in the order they appear in the text:",
        "respuesta": "In 1961. Kennedy began NASA’s work on a manned moon landing. You might think we’ve made thousands of space trips. but it’s not easy. Let’s explore the history, key dates, and why we celebrate National Moon Day. On May 25th. Kennedy launched NASA’s Apollo program to land an American on the moon.",
        "opciones": [
            "You might think we’ve made thousands of space trips. but it’s not easy. Let’s explore the history",
            " key dates",
            " and why we celebrate National Moon Day.",
            "On May 25th. Kennedy launched NASA’s Apollo program to land an American on the moon.",
            "In 1961. Kennedy began NASA’s work on a manned moon landing."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 35,
        "id_actividad": 72,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Match",
        "pregunta": "Match each event with its corresponding year:",
        "respuesta": "Americans watch as the first humans land on the moon.,1969,NASA's Apollo program comes to an end with a final manned landing: Apollo 17.,1972,First manned flight on NASA's Apollo eight repeats its orbit around the moon ten times.,1968",
        "opciones": [
            "Americans watch as the first humans land on the moon.",
            "1968",
            "NASA's Apollo program comes to an end with a final manned landing: Apollo 17.",
            "1972",
            "First manned flight on NASA's Apollo eight repeats its orbit around the moon ten times.",
            "1969\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 35,
        "id_actividad": 78,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following words to form a coherent sentence:",
        "respuesta": "The first humans land on Apollo 11 mission.",
        "opciones": [
            "Apollo",
            "11",
            "The first",
            "humans",
            "land",
            "on",
            "mission."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 36,
        "id_actividad": 54,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Order the following phrases to reflect the chronological sequence of events mentioned in the text:",
        "respuesta": "NASA announced the moon landing as being “the single greatest technological achievement of all time” President Kennedy started NASA's work on a man’s lunar landing. Americans watch as the first manned flight on NASA's Apollo eight repeats its orbit around the moon ten times.",
        "opciones": [
            "President Kennedy started NASA's work on a man’s lunar landing.",
            "Americans watch as the first manned flight on NASA's Apollo eight repeats its orbit around the moon ten times.",
            "NASA announced the moon landing as being “the single greatest technological achievement of all time”.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 36,
        "id_actividad": 62,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "What is the significance of President Kennedy's announcement about NASA's Apollo program?",
        "respuesta": "It marked the beginning of efforts to land a man on the moon.,It emphasized the importance of space exploration.",
        "opciones": [
            "It marked the beginning of efforts to land a man on the moon.",
            "It emphasized the importance of space exploration.",
            "It signaled the end of the Cold War.",
            "It led to the development of unmanned space probes.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 36,
        "id_actividad": 71,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following sentences in the order they appear in the text:",
        "respuesta": "President Nixon's declaration of National Moon Landing Day. President Kennedy's announcement of NASA's Apollo space program. The first televised images of the moon's surface transmitted by NASA's unmanned probe Ranger 7.",
        "opciones": [
            "\"President Kennedy's announcement of NASA's Apollo space program.",
            "The first televised images of the moon's surface transmitted by NASA's unmanned probe Ranger 7.",
            "President Nixon's declaration of National Moon Landing Day.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 36,
        "id_actividad": 79,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Put the words in the correct order to form a sentence:",
        "respuesta": "National Moon Day celebrates the first landing on anniversary.",
        "opciones": [
            "National",
            "Moon",
            "Day",
            "celebrates",
            "the",
            "landing",
            "first",
            "on",
            "anniversary."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 37,
        "id_actividad": 55,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following phrases in chronological order according to the milestones of the space progra",
        "respuesta": "Apollo 11 carried the first humans to the moon. President Nixon declares National Moon Landing Day on July 20th to celebrate the anniversary of man's first moon landing. NASA's Apollo program comes to an end with a final manned landing: Apollo 17.",
        "opciones": [
            "President Nixon declares National Moon Landing Day on July 20th to celebrate the anniversary of man's first moon landing.",
            "Apollo 11 carried the first humans to the moon.",
            "NASA's Apollo program comes to an end with a final manned landing: Apollo 17.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 5.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 37,
        "id_actividad": 63,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Sort the words to form the correct sentence:",
        "respuesta": "Americans watched the first moon landing.",
        "opciones": [
            "the",
            "moon",
            "landing.",
            "first",
            "on",
            "Americans",
            "watched"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 5.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 37,
        "id_actividad": 80,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the words to create a meaningful sentence:",
        "respuesta": "Astronauts Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin Apollo 11.",
        "opciones": [
            "Apollo",
            "11.",
            "astronauts",
            "Neil",
            "Armstrong",
            "and",
            "Buzz",
            "Aldrin"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 5.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 38,
        "id_actividad": 56,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Order the following phrases to reflect the sequence of the Apollo 11 moon landing:",
        "respuesta": "In the command module, there was a third astronaut. pilot Michael Collins. He waited alone in orbit until Armstrong and Aldrin returned. Neil Armstrong was the very first person that steps on the moon. Buzz Aldrin was the second man to step onto the moon's surface.",
        "opciones": [
            "Neil Armstrong was the very first person that steps on the moon.",
            "Buzz Aldrin was the second man to step onto the moon's surface.",
            "In the command module",
            " there was a third astronaut. pilot Michael Collins. He waited alone in orbit until Armstrong and Aldrin returned.\"\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 6.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 38,
        "id_actividad": 64,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Sort the words to form the correct sentence:",
        "respuesta": "How do you plan to celebrate National Moon Landing Day?",
        "opciones": [
            "celebrate",
            "Day?",
            "to",
            "National",
            "Landing",
            "Moon",
            "How",
            "do",
            "you",
            "plan"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 6.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 38,
        "id_actividad": 73,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Match",
        "pregunta": "Match each quote with the person who said it:",
        "respuesta": "One small step for man, one giant leap for mankind.,Neil Armstrong,I believe that this nation should commit itself to achieving the goal. before this decade is out. of landing a man on the moon and returning him safely to the earth.,John F. Kennedy",
        "opciones": [
            "One small step for man",
            " one giant leap for mankind.",
            "John F. Kennedy",
            "I believe that this nation should commit itself to achieving the goal. before this decade is out. of landing a man on the moon and returning him safely to the earth.",
            "Neil Armstrong"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 6.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 39,
        "id_actividad": 57,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Mach",
        "pregunta": "Match each space program milestone with the year it occurred:",
        "respuesta": "First manned flight on NASA's Apollo eight repeats its orbit around the moon ten times.,1968,Americans watch as the first humans land on the moon.,1969,NASA's Apollo program comes to an end with a final manned landing: Apollo 17.,1972\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "First manned flight on NASA's Apollo eight repeats its orbit around the moon ten times.",
            "1972",
            "Americans watch as the first humans land on the moon.",
            "1969",
            "NASA's Apollo program comes to an end with a final manned landing: Apollo 17.",
            "1968\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 7.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 39,
        "id_actividad": 65,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Sort the words to form the correct sentence:",
        "respuesta": "I believe this nation should achieve this goal itself.",
        "opciones": [
            "achieve",
            "nation",
            "should",
            "goal",
            "this",
            "itself.",
            "to",
            "I",
            "believe"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 7.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 39,
        "id_actividad": 74,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Match",
        "pregunta": "Match each significance with the corresponding event:",
        "respuesta": "President Kennedy's announcement of NASA's Apollo space program.,Signaled the beginning of efforts to land a man on the moon.,The first televised images of the moon's surface transmitted by NASA's unmanned probe Ranger 7.,Provided unprecedented visual information about the moon's surface.",
        "opciones": [
            "President Kennedy's announcement of NASA's Apollo space program.",
            "Signaled the beginning of efforts to land a man on the moon.",
            "The first televised images of the moon's surface transmitted by NASA's unmanned probe Ranger 7.",
            "Provided unprecedented visual information about the moon's surface."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 7.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 40,
        "id_actividad": 58,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Mach",
        "pregunta": "Match each famous quote with the person who said it:",
        "respuesta": "That's one small step for a man. one giant leap for mankind.,Neil Armstrong,I believe that this nation should commit itself to achieving the goal. before this decade is out. of landing a man on the moon and returning him safely to tthe earth.,John F. Kennedy",
        "opciones": [
            "That's one small step for a man. one giant leap for mankind.",
            "John F. Kennedy",
            "I believe that this nation should commit itself to achieving the goal. before this decade is out. of landing a man on the moon and returning him safely to tthe earth.",
            "Neil Armstrong"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 8.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 40,
        "id_actividad": 66,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "What is true about National Moon Day?",
        "respuesta": "It commemorates the first moon landing.",
        "opciones": [
            "It celebrates the Moon's birthday.",
            "It commemorates the first moon landing.",
            "It is a holiday honoring astronauts.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 8.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 40,
        "id_actividad": 75,
        "id_unidad": 2,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "Which of the following statements accurately describe the significance of the Apollo 11 mission?",
        "respuesta": "It was the first mission to successfully land astronauts on the moon.",
        "opciones": [
            "It marked the first time humans landed on Mars.",
            "It was the final mission of the Apollo program.",
            "It was the first mission to successfully land astronauts on the moon.",
            "It was led by astronaut John F. Kennedy.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Moon Landing 8.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 12,
        "id_actividad": 14,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following phrases in the order they appear in the episode:",
        "respuesta": "I’m a big fat dynamo! Get a load of King-Size Homer! I’m just too fat. It’s not a sprain; it’s fatness.\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "It’s not a sprain; it’s fatness.",
            "I’m a big fat dynamo!",
            "Get a load of King-Size Homer!",
            "I’m just too fat.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 12,
        "id_actividad": 24,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "Who is referred to as Hydra's number one thug in the script?",
        "respuesta": "Baron Strucker",
        "opciones": [
            "Tony Stark",
            "Steve Rogers",
            "Baron Strucker",
            "Dr. Helen Cho\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 12,
        "id_actividad": 36,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following sentence in the correct order:",
        "respuesta": "Ultron reveals his plan to save the world and destroy the Avengers",
        "opciones": [
            "the world and destroy",
            "Ultron reveals his plan to save",
            "the Avengers."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 12,
        "id_actividad": 47,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "What reasons does Ultron give for wanting to confront the Avengers? Select all that apply:",
        "respuesta": "To end the Avengers,To achieve harmony and peace",
        "opciones": [
            "To protect the world",
            "To end the Avengers",
            "To seek revenge for past actions",
            "To achieve harmony and peace",
            "To prove his superiority over humanity\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 13,
        "id_actividad": 15,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Match",
        "pregunta": "Match the following characters with their actions:",
        "respuesta": "Warns Homer about his health risks,Marge,Suggests an all-fat diet,Dr. Nick,Helps Homer in gaining weight,Bart,Reacts with disappointment to Homer’s weight plan,Homer",
        "opciones": [
            "Warns Homer about his health risks",
            "Homer",
            "Suggests an all-fat diet",
            "Dr. Nick",
            "Helps Homer in gaining weight",
            "Bart",
            "Reacts with disappointment to Homer’s weight plan",
            "Marge"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 13,
        "id_actividad": 25,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "What is the primary reason for Clint Barton's inability to lift Thor's hammer?",
        "respuesta": "He is unworthy",
        "opciones": [
            "He lacks physical strength",
            "He is unworthy",
            "The hammer is too heavy",
            "It's a trick\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 13,
        "id_actividad": 37,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Put the following words in the right sequence:",
        "respuesta": "The Avengers assemble to battle Ultron and his army.",
        "opciones": [
            "Ultron and",
            "The Avengers assemble to battle",
            "his army."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 14,
        "id_actividad": 26,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "What does Ultron claim is the only path to peace?",
        "respuesta": "Extinction of the Avengers",
        "opciones": [
            "Surrender",
            "Negotiation",
            "Destruction",
            "Extinction of the Avengers\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 14,
        "id_actividad": 38,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Rearrange the words to form a coherent sentence:",
        "respuesta": "Wanda and Pietro volunteer for Strucker's experiments.",
        "opciones": [
            "Wanda",
            "Strucker's experiments.",
            "and Pietro volunteer for"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 15,
        "id_actividad": 27,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following phrases in the order they appear in the script:",
        "respuesta": "Where's Loki's scepter? Technically. I'm a thug for SHIELD. I'll put it right under illegal human experimentation. Well then technically you're unemployed. ",
        "opciones": [
            "I'll put it right under illegal human experimentation.",
            "Where's Loki's scepter?",
            "Technically. I'm a thug for SHIELD.",
            "Well then technically you're unemployed.\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 15,
        "id_actividad": 39,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "What is the primary reason for the Avengers infiltrating the HYDRA base in Sokovia?",
        "respuesta": "To retrieve Loki's scepter",
        "opciones": [
            "To retrieve Loki's scepter",
            "To rescue hostages",
            "To apprehend Baron Strucker",
            "To gather intel on HYDRA's plans\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 15,
        "id_actividad": 48,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Rearrange the words to form a coherent sentence:",
        "respuesta": "The twins were experimented on by Strucker's.",
        "opciones": [
            "experimented",
            "Strucker's.",
            "on",
            "they",
            "were",
            "by",
            "twins",
            "The"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 16,
        "id_actividad": 28,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following phrases in the order they appear in the script:",
        "respuesta": "We have an enhanced in the field. Stark. we really need to get inside. It's too soon. My men can hold them.",
        "opciones": [
            "We have an enhanced in the field.",
            "Stark. we really need to get inside.",
            "It's too soon.",
            "My men can hold them.\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 5.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 16,
        "id_actividad": 40,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "Who among the Avengers demonstrates enhanced abilities during the battle at the HYDRA base?",
        "respuesta": "Steve Rogers",
        "opciones": [
            "Tony Stark",
            "Natasha Romanoff",
            "Steve Rogers",
            "Clint Barton\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 5.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 16,
        "id_actividad": 49,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Rearrange the words to form a coherent sentence:",
        "respuesta": "The central building is protected by some kind of energy shield.",
        "opciones": [
            "energy",
            "protected",
            "The",
            "building",
            "by",
            "shield.",
            "is",
            "some",
            "kind",
            "of",
            "central",
            "The"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 5.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 17,
        "id_actividad": 29,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following phrases in the order they appear in the script:",
        "respuesta": "Hello. I am JARVIS. You are Ultron. a global peace-keeping initiative designed by Mr. Stark. Tony. This feels weird. This feels wrong. I am a program. I am without form.",
        "opciones": [
            "I am a program. I am without form.",
            "This feels weird. This feels wrong.",
            "Tony.",
            "Hello. I am JARVIS. You are Ultron. a global peace-keeping initiative designed by Mr. Stark.\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 6.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 17,
        "id_actividad": 41,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "What prompts Tony Stark to initiate the Ultron program?",
        "respuesta": "Strucker's experiments with the scepter",
        "opciones": [
            "Fear of a new alien invasion",
            "Desire for global peace",
            "Strucker's experiments with the scepter",
            "Fury's orders\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 6.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 17,
        "id_actividad": 50,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Rearrange the words to form a coherent sentence:",
        "respuesta": "The Avengers are in the process of infiltrating a HYDRA base in Sokovia.",
        "opciones": [
            "base",
            "The",
            "Avengers",
            "infiltrating",
            "process",
            "are",
            "the",
            "in",
            "of",
            "a",
            "HYDRA",
            "Sokovia."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 6.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 18,
        "id_actividad": 30,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Match",
        "pregunta": "Match the following descriptions with the corresponding characters from the text:",
        "respuesta": "Limited battle experience but enhanced skills.,Bruce Banner,SHIELD agent with a cynical outlook,Natasha Romanoff,A shapeless computer program,JARVIS,Designer of the Ultron program,Tony Stark,Creator of an artificial intelligence named JARVIS.,Tony Stark",
        "opciones": [
            "Limited battle experience but enhanced skills.",
            "Tony Stark",
            "SHIELD agent with a cynical outlook.",
            "Hawkeye",
            "A shapeless computer program.",
            "JARVIS",
            "Designer of the Ultron program.",
            "Natasha Romanoff",
            "Creator of an artificial intelligence named JARVIS.",
            "Bruce Banner"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 7.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 18,
        "id_actividad": 42,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following sentences in the correct order:",
        "respuesta": "Guys. stop. we gotta talk this through. Do you see a power source for that shield? Stark. we really need to get inside. I'm closing in.\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "Stark. we really need to get inside.",
            "I'm closing in.",
            "Do you see a power source for that shield?",
            "Guys. stop. we gotta talk this through.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 7.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 19,
        "id_actividad": 31,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Match",
        "pregunta": "Match the following phrases with the corresponding events from the text:",
        "respuesta": "Where is Loki's scepter?,Natasha Romanoff mentions the location of Loki's scepter.,We've got enhanced on the field.,Bruce Banner transforms into Hulk during a battle.,I'll put it right under 'Illegal Human Experimentation.',Tony Stark and Steve Rogers have a discussion about the plan.",
        "opciones": [
            "Where is Loki's scepter?",
            "Natasha Romanoff mentions the location of Loki's scepter.",
            "We've got enhanced on the field.",
            "Bruce Banner transforms into Hulk during a battle.",
            "I'll put it right under 'Illegal Human Experimentation.'",
            "Tony Stark and Steve Rogers have a discussion about the plan."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 8.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 19,
        "id_actividad": 43,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following sentences in the correct order:",
        "respuesta": "This one, this very vulnerable blue one? It needs Ultron. Our job is 'if'. I've seen colder. Peace in our time. Imagine that.\"\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "I've seen colder.",
            "Peace in our time. Imagine that.",
            "Our job is 'if'.",
            "This one",
            " this very vulnerable blue one? It needs Ultron.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 8.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 20,
        "id_actividad": 32,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Match",
        "pregunta": "Match the following elements with their corresponding descriptions from the text:",
        "respuesta": "Artificial intelligence program.,JARVIS,Scientific experiment resulting in a threat to humanity,Ultron,Weapon of great power created by a Norse god.,SHIELD,Covert organization dedicated to global security.,Loki's Scepter,Hero with archery skills.,Hawkeye",
        "opciones": [
            "Artificial intelligence program.",
            "Ultron",
            "Scientific experiment resulting in a threat to humanity",
            "Loki's Scepter",
            "Weapon of great power created by a Norse god.",
            "SHIELD",
            "Covert organization dedicated to global security.",
            "JARVIS",
            "\nHero with archery skills",
            "Hawkeye\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 9.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 20,
        "id_actividad": 44,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following sentences in the correct order:",
        "respuesta": "You've had a tough week. What mission? Everyone creates the thing they dread. But you will tear them apart, from the inside.\"",
        "opciones": [
            "Everyone creates the thing they dread.",
            "What mission?",
            "You've had a tough week.",
            "But you will tear them apart",
            " from the inside.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 9.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 21,
        "id_actividad": 33,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "Which of the following Avengers appeared in the movie \"Avengers: Age of Ultron\"? ",
        "respuesta": "Iron Man,Hulk,Black Widow",
        "opciones": [
            "Iron Man",
            "Thor",
            "Hulk",
            "Black Widow",
            "Spider-Man\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 10.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 21,
        "id_actividad": 34,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "Which of the following locations were featured in the movie \"Avengers: Age of Ultron\"?",
        "respuesta": "Sokovia,Seoul",
        "opciones": [
            "New York City",
            "Sokovia",
            "Wakanda",
            "Seoul",
            "London\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 10.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 21,
        "id_actividad": 45,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "Which Avengers were present during the infiltration of the HYDRA base? Select all that apply:",
        "respuesta": "Tony Stark,Steve Rogers,Natasha Romanoff, Thor,Clint Barton",
        "opciones": [
            "Tony Stark",
            "Steve Rogers",
            "Natasha Romanoff",
            "Thor",
            "Clint Barton\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 10.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 22,
        "id_actividad": 35,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "Which of the following characters were involved in creating or confronting Ultron in \"Avengers: Age ",
        "respuesta": "Tony Stark,Bruce Banner,Steve Rogers",
        "opciones": [
            "Tony Stark",
            "Bruce Banner",
            "Steve Rogers",
            "Natasha Romanoff",
            "Thor\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 11.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 22,
        "id_actividad": 46,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "Which abilities do the Maximoff twins possess? Select all that apply:",
        "respuesta": "Increased metabolism,Telekinesis,Neural electric interfacing",
        "opciones": [
            "Increased metabolism",
            "Improved thermal homeostasis",
            "Telekinesis",
            "Enhanced strength",
            "Neural electric interfacing\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Avengers Age of Ultron 11.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 23,
        "id_actividad": 81,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "Why do the characters decide to split up?",
        "respuesta": "Because they are being hunted and need to divert authorities' attention.",
        "opciones": [
            "Because they have different plans.",
            "Because they are being hunted and need to divert authorities' attention.",
            "Because they want to ensure their family's safety.",
            "Because they want to throw a party.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 23,
        "id_actividad": 104,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "What does the speaker imply about the rarity of the cars?",
        "respuesta": "There are only four cars in the Western Hemisphere.",
        "opciones": [
            "There are only four cars left in the world.",
            "There are only four cars in the Western Hemisphere.",
            "There are only four cars available for sale.",
            "There are only four cars owned by the speaker.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 1.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 24,
        "id_actividad": 82,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "Which methods do the characters prefer to gain power?",
        "respuesta": "Diplomatic and exchange methods.\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "Violent methods.",
            "Diplomatic and exchange methods.",
            "Emotional manipulation methods.",
            "Random methods.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 24,
        "id_actividad": 105,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "What does the speaker imply about the lady mentioned?",
        "respuesta": "She is attractive.,She is influential.\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "She is kind.",
            "She is wealthy.",
            "She is attractive.",
            "She is generous.",
            "She is influential.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 2.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 25,
        "id_actividad": 83,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Select",
        "pregunta": "What resources did the Portuguese offer the natives to gain their cooperation?",
        "respuesta": "Mirrors. scissors. and trinkets.",
        "opciones": [
            "Mirrors. scissors. and trinkets.",
            "Weapons and ammunition.",
            "Money and gold.",
            "Exotic animals.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 25,
        "id_actividad": 106,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "What is the speaker's response to the suggestion of driving in a particular car?",
        "respuesta": "Disbelief,Excitement\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "Agreement",
            "Disbelief",
            "Disinterest",
            "Anger",
            "Excitement\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 3.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 26,
        "id_actividad": 84,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following phrases in the order they appear in the dialogue:",
        "respuesta": "Which means we just jumped to the top of the wanted list. Where's Vince? That's a good question. He'll be here. Guys. we're all over the news. They're blaming us for the killing of those D.E.A agents on the train.\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "Where's Vince?",
            "That's a good question.",
            "He'll be here.",
            "Guys. we're all over the news. They're blaming us for the killing of those D.E.A agents on the train.",
            "Which means we just jumped to the top of the wanted list.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 26,
        "id_actividad": 107,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Order the Phrase",
        "respuesta": "Are everyone's boats ready for the?",
        "opciones": [
            "the",
            "for",
            "ready",
            "?",
            "Are everyone's boats"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 4.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 27,
        "id_actividad": 85,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following phrases in the correct order:",
        "respuesta": "They're gonna be looking for the three of us together now. Not just fast. We got a hard right and a hairpin. We're gonna need something agile. We're gonna need some real fast cars to get through this. Can't we just tap in and replace the image? Yeah. That's a narrow window. man.",
        "opciones": [
            "We're gonna need some real fast cars to get through this.",
            "Can't we just tap in and replace the image?",
            "Yeah. That's a narrow window. man.",
            "They're gonna be looking for the three of us together now.",
            "Not just fast. We got a hard right and a hairpin. We're gonna need something agile.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 5.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 27,
        "id_actividad": 108,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Order the Phrase",
        "respuesta": "They'll work hard. but they'll succeed.",
        "opciones": [
            "They'll work hard.but",
            "succeed.",
            "they'll"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 5.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 28,
        "id_actividad": 86,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following phrases in their sequence in the dialogue:",
        "respuesta": "I got eyes on Nico now. We need to move. We don't have that much time. Are you crazy. Dom? We can't. It's a suicide mission. Not to run away, to finish the job. I got us a flight out. We can leave Rio in the rearview in the next five hours.\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "I got us a flight out. We can leave Rio in the rearview in the next five hours.",
            "Are you crazy. Dom? We can't.",
            "It's a suicide mission.",
            "Not to run away",
            " to finish the job.",
            "I got eyes on Nico now. We need to move. We don't have that much time.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 6.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 28,
        "id_actividad": 109,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Order the Phrase",
        "respuesta": "How we gonna explain this?\"",
        "opciones": [
            "this",
            "How we",
            "gonna explain?"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 6.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 29,
        "id_actividad": 87,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Complete",
        "pregunta": "Complete the Sentences:",
        "respuesta": "find,Seek,Locate",
        "opciones": [
            "We find out what it is",
            " we'll know what we're up against?"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 7.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 29,
        "id_actividad": 88,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Complete",
        "pregunta": "Complete the Sentences:",
        "respuesta": "Because,Since,As",
        "opciones": [
            "Because something's in it",
            " we'll know what we're up against"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 7.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 29,
        "id_actividad": 89,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Complete",
        "pregunta": "Complete the Sentences:",
        "respuesta": "bigger,big,large",
        "opciones": [
            "Our family just got bigger. Salud. mi familia!"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 7.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 30,
        "id_actividad": 90,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "What methods do the characters prefer to gain power?",
        "respuesta": "Diplomatic and exchange methods.",
        "opciones": [
            "Violent methods.",
            "Diplomatic and exchange methods.",
            "Emotional manipulation methods.",
            "Random methods.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 8.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 30,
        "id_actividad": 91,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "Why do the characters decide to split up?",
        "respuesta": "Because they are being hunted and need to divert authorities' attention.\r\n\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "Because they have different plans.",
            "Because they are being hunted and need to divert authorities' attention.",
            "Because they want to ensure their family's safety.",
            "Because they want to throw a party.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 8.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 30,
        "id_actividad": 92,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Multiple Choice",
        "pregunta": "What resources did the Portuguese offer the natives to gain their cooperation?",
        "respuesta": "Mirrors. scissors. and trinkets.\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "Mirrors. scissors. and trinkets.",
            "Weapons and ammunition.",
            "Money and gold.",
            "Exotic animals.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 8.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 31,
        "id_actividad": 93,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following words to form a coherent sentence:",
        "respuesta": "See. now I see why you're always getting into accidents. You can't even drive a damn remote control car. You can't drive.",
        "opciones": [
            "You can't drive.",
            "See. now I see why you’re always getting into accidents.",
            " You can’t even drive a damn remote control car."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 9.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 31,
        "id_actividad": 94,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Put the following words in the correct order to form a sentence:",
        "respuesta": "Right this way. my dear.",
        "opciones": [
            "my dear.",
            "Right this way."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 9.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 31,
        "id_actividad": 95,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following words to form a coherent sentence:",
        "respuesta": "You turn around and put your hands behind your back. Real tough",
        "opciones": [
            "Real tough.",
            "You turn around and put your hands behind your back."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 9.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 32,
        "id_actividad": 99,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Order",
        "pregunta": "Arrange the following sentences in the correct order as they appear in the dialogue:",
        "respuesta": "He’ll be here. We gotta get out of here. We find out what it is. we’ll know what we’re up against.\r\n",
        "opciones": [
            "We gotta get out of here.",
            "We find out what it is. we’ll know what we’re up against.",
            "He’ll be here.\r\n"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 10.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 32,
        "id_actividad": 100,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Mach",
        "pregunta": "Mach",
        "respuesta": "Our family just got bigger.,You and Mia head south. I’ll lead them away.,I’m not going anywhere.,They’re gonna be looking for the three of us together now.,Dom? Promise me we stick together.,We need to split up.",
        "opciones": [
            "Our family just got bigger.",
            "You and Mia head south. I’ll lead them away.",
            "I’m not going anywhere.",
            "They’re gonna be looking for the three of us together now.",
            "Dom? Promise me we stick together.",
            "We need to split up.\""
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 10.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 32,
        "id_actividad": 101,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Complete",
        "pregunta": "Complete the Sentences:",
        "respuesta": "fast, faster, slow ",
        "opciones": [
            "We’re gonna need some real fast cars to get through this."
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 10.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 32,
        "id_actividad": 102,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Complete",
        "pregunta": "Complete the Sentences:",
        "respuesta": "slow,agile,fast",
        "opciones": [
            "Not just fast. We got a hard right and a hairpin. We’re gonna need something agile"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 10.mp4"
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "tipo": "Activity",
        "id_recurso": 32,
        "id_actividad": 103,
        "id_unidad": 3,
        "descripcion": "Complete",
        "pregunta": "Complete the Sentences:",
        "respuesta": "Bryan,Toretto,Mia",
        "opciones": [
            "I’ll see you soon. Toretto"
        ],
        "ruta_video": "../Publico/archivos/Fast and Furious V 10.mp4"
    }
];